

+33 6 95 24 43 62

olivier.eeckhoutte@gmail.com Location: Morbihan, France

CONTACT INFORMATIONS

Professional Blog: https://leandeep.com (Articles

about my technical skills)

Linkedin: https://bit.ly/oeeckhout (Detailed profile)

Olivier Eeckhoutte

Freelance Solution Architect / Tech Lead / Blockchain & Web development Expert / DevOps

PROFILE

I feel lucky to work in a field I am passionated about.

Passionated about new technologies and very curious, I like to design and develop useful solutions and solve complex problems.

I enjoy learning new things all the time, be more and more proficient, discover raw gems and share my new discoveries with others.

I spent 3 years in the USA. Remote worker

EDUCATION

Engineer of "Ecole Centrale de Lille", Graduated in 2011

Top Engineering School

Entrepreneurship and Management
Specialities

Member of Iteem program. Second diploma in Management delivered by Skema Business School

Udacity, Georgia Tech, Kaggle, 2016 - 2017

NanoDegree Program, 420 hours of online training about Machine Learning

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance, Lean Deep

Nov 2019 - Today (TAG Heuer, Switzerland - Lead DevOps)

- Worked on Cloud & Python based intermediary platform (i.e: Enterprise Service Bus also called Middleware) and API between the Ecom website, Retail systems and all internal backends systems (i.e: SAP, Salesforce, Cegid and lot's of Ecom related internal systems & SAAS...). More on this successful innovative platform here https://bit.ly/3gs0EHY and here: This is my personal feedback (Meetup recorded in France): https://bit.ly/3C0hX9W
- Contributed to the enterprise custom customer IAM
- Contributed to a new Ecom headless platform and other Web based platforms
- Managed different Azure/ Kubernetes migrations and setup all kind of different automations (Terraform, CI/CD, Testing, Monitoring...)
- Creation of an enterprise cross-channels Business Activity
 Monitoring (BAM) using a data stack (i.e: pandas...)
- Problems solver
- International team

Apr 2019 - Nov 19 (Engie, Brussels - Senior Software Engineer/ Tech Lead)

- Create reusable and transversal tools for the developer teams
 (Data access management, automated end to end tests tools)
- Co-Technical Lead in an international team made of developers, data engineers & data analysts
- Migration to AWS

KEY SKILLS

Architecture

Design & Architecture Patterns
(some concepts I already used:
Clean Architecture, CQRS
(Command Query Responsibility
Segregation), Cloud-Native,
Serverless, Micro Services, API
Gateway, Service Mesh, Service
Oriented Architecture, Message
Oriented Architecture with Kafka...)
SQL, NoSQL (MongoDB, Redis,
CouchBase, ElasticSearch,
BigQuery, DynamoDB, Postgres...)
SSO (keycloak), Oauth2, Vault, UML,
loT, Enterprise Workflows
(Camunda), Edge computing (Jetson)

Data Science/ Al

TensorFlow/ Keras, Python, Deep Learning, Machine Learning (scikit-learn, Pandas), FastAl, RPA (UIPath), Scaping, Chatbots, AWS Al tools, Kubeflow, Prefect, Airflow, Pytorch

DevOps/ Cloud

Azure, Amazon Web Services,
Docker, Monitoring, Tests
Automation, Linux (RedHat 7,
CentOS, Debian), Continuous
Delivery, Software Factory (Github,
AWS CodePipeline, Gitlab, CircleCl,
Azure Devops), Nginx, Kubernetes (+
operators), OpenShift (v3.6 to v4),
Hub & Spoke Architecture,
Terraform, 12 Factors

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Feb 2018 - Apr 2019 (Adeo Services - Cloud Architect / SRE / DevOps)

- Setup and Manage large Platform As A Service (> 300 servers)
- Cloud Hybrid (On-Premise Google Cloud Platform)
- DevOps, Cloud Native Architecture
- Trainings creation and animation (Kubernetes, CI/CD Tools, Openshift, Continuous Delivery)
- Agile Methodology training and technical evangelisation
- SRE (Site Reliability Engineering): development, automation, monitoring (Python, Ansible, Terraform, Prometheus...)

Sept 2018 - Dec 2018 (Short contract 1 day a week)

- DataHub solution setup on AWS EKS (Managed Kubernetes)
- Plateforme CKAN deployment
- Data collection automation

Web3 trader, 70 Cent (in parallel of my freelance activity)

Jul 2020 - Today (70 Cent, France - DeFi / Web3 Trader)

- Who better than yourself can take care of your finances?
- As I don't believe banks or other financial institutions will really take care of my money I simply automate everything to make my personal portfolio grow by trading on crypto (CeFI and DeFi) exchanges and by building decision making bots

Technical Leader / Solution Architect / Data Champion, SwissLife France

Mar 2015 - Feb 2018

- Technical Lead "Digital Solutions" (Design and development of the main customer portal)
- Transversal communities (Developers & DevOps) animator
- Dissemination of Agile & Software Craftsmanship Tooling -Continuous Delivery best practices
- Data Champion (Big Data /Machine Learning / Cloud migration contributor)
- Applicative Architecture Design
- Many innovation Studies and Proof Of Concept done
- Cognitive technologies referent

KEY SKILLS

Blockchain

Nodes hosting, DeFi & DeFi protocols, Advanced backend Web3 development, Solidity, **Rust**, Security, Hardhat

Web/ Mobile

Javascript (AngularJS, Angular 2+, Ionic, Backbone...), Single Page App, Responsive Web Design, NodeJS, Webpack, HTML5 (WebRTC, WebSockets...), Cordova, iOS, Android, PHP, Java, TypeScript, Vue, Progressive Web Apps, TDD, BDD, DDD

Project management/ Methods

Scrum, Kanban, Holacracy, Software Craftsmanship, Lean Management, Lean Startup, Design Thinking

LANGUAGES



HOBBIES

DIY Creative workshops Woodworking Beerology **Bicking** Travels Windsurfing Walking in Nature Wing foil Sailing Standup Paddle Investing Biking Cooking Coding Micro-nutrition -Reading Judo Tech or Financial Hacking podcasts while running

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Entrepreneurship in parallel of my activity at Swisslife

Apr 2016 - Feb 2018

- Design and development of IoT object
- Trainer in Project Management with Scrum, Lean Startup and Holacracy, Advanced JavaScript
- Innovation Workshop Organisation
- Startup Advisor (Architecture) et Instructor AngularJS, Nodejs
- Backend Development (REST, NodeJS & MongoDB)
- Automatic Tensorflow Models trainings engine manageable with Web/Mobile interface
- Deep Learning on Mobile devices and OTA updates
- Big Data & Machine Learning Lille Meetup Administrator
- Few technical conferences speeches given (i.e: Nutigo...)

CTO, Geophyle France (startup of 15 people)

Feb 2014 - Mar 2015

- Team Management (7 developers)
- Architecture, Design and development of the solutions
- Projet Management (Budget / Planning / Ressources)
- Recruiting

Application Architect, Schneider-Electric France

Mar 2013 - Feb 2014

- Startup Creation Intrapreneurship project
- Facility Management Cross-Platforms Application (https://youtu.be/gl9t-XTco18)
- Architecture & Development lead (AWS, Web, Mobile, NoSQL)

Team/ Technical Leader, Schneider-Electric USA

Jul 2009 - Mar 2013

- Mobile Cross-Platforms architectures design & development
- Technical advisor in the strategy & Innovation department
- Mobile development Companies buyout auditor

Other Experiences

- Developer, Arc International (2 months internship 2008)
- Seller plumbing shelf (3 months internship 2007)
- At home computers repair (from 2005 to 2008)

RECOMMANDATIONS ON DEMAND

TRAININGS & CERTIFICATIONS

- 2021 Ethereum and Solidity Developer Bootcamp, MOOC
- 2020 Forex trading with Ichimoku, MOOC
- 2019 Typescript fundamentals, MOOC
- 2019 Learning Blockchain Dev with EOS and C++, MOOC
- 2018 Google Cloud Platform introduction, Google
- 2018 Kubernetes, MOOC
- 2017 Certif. Lean Management Introduction, Advanced Path
- 2017 Data Science, Advanced level, OCTO, Paris
- 2016 Data Science foundations, OCTO, Paris
- 2016 Certif. AWS Solutions Architect Associate
- 2016 Certif. Machine Learning Andrew NG, MOOC
- 2016 Certif. Intermediate Python For Data Science, Datacamp
- 2016 Amazon Web Services for Data Science, MOOC
- 2016 Mastering Software Development, Arolla, Paris
- 2016 Holacracy, IGI Partners, Training + 4 month mentoring
- 2013 CEH v7 Training and Certification, Sysdream, Paris
- 2012 Certif. Energy Manager Professional, Schneider, Boston